A Guide to the Astoria Manuscript, ca. 1835
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Astoria Manuscript ca. 1835
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6256-am
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the library by Marion Kingsford Trousoff on 9 June 1992.
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains a holograph manuscript of Washington Irving's Astoria, consisting of chapters one through four and chapters fifty through sixty-one.
Contents List
- Astoria, Chapter 1, by Washington Irving ca. 1835, AMs, 27 l., summary on unnumbered leaf at the beginning, and remaining leaves numbered 1-26.
- Astoria, Chapter 2, by Washington Irving ca. 1835, AMs, 11 l., numbered 1-4, and 24-30.
- Astoria, Chapter 3, by Washington Irving ca. 1835, AMs, 29 l., summary on unnumbered leaf at the beginning, remaining leaves numbered 1-27, with page 17 on two separate leaves, the second unnumbered.
- Astoria, Chapter 4, by Washington Irving ca. 1835, AMs, 18 l., summary on unnumbered leaf at the beginning, and remaining leaves numbered 1-16, with page 8 consisting of two separate leaves both numbered 8.
- Astoria, Chapter 50, by Washington Irving ca. 1835, AMs, 18 l., summary and page 1 unnumbered at the beginning, and remaining leaves numbered 2-17.
- Astoria, Chapter 51, by Washington Irving ca. 1835, AMs, 11 l., page 1 unnumbered and the remaining leaves numbered 2-11.
- Astoria, Chapter 52, by Washington Irving ca. 1835, AMs, 15 l., summary and page one on unnumbered leaf at the beginning, remaining leaves numbered 2-8; and new numbering of leaves 4-10 at the end of the chapter.
- Astoria, Chapter 53, by Washington Irving ca. 1835, AMs, 25 l., numbered 1-23, lacking a leaf numbered 15; and with page 5 on 2 leaves and page 6 on 3 leaves.
- Astoria, Chapter 54, by Washington Irving ca. 1835, AMs, 8 l., page 1 on unnumbered leaf, and remaining leaves numbered 2-8.
- Astoria, Chapter 55, by Washington Irving ca. 1835, AMs, 5 l., page 1 unnumbered and the remaining leaves numbered 2-5.
- Astoria, Chapter 56, by Washington Irving ca. 1835, AMs, 9 l., page 1 on an unnumbered leaf and remaining leaves numbered 2-9.
- Astoria, Chapter 57, by Washington Irving ca. 1835, AMs, 17 l., page 1 unnumbered and the remaining leaves numbered 2-17.
- Astoria, Chapter 58, by Washington Irving ca. 1835, AMs, 16 l., page 1 unnumbered, lacking a leaf numbered 2; and remaining leave numbered 3-14, with page 12 on 3 leavesand page 14 on 2 leaves.
- Astoria, Chapter 59, by Washington Irving ca. 1835, AMs, 11 l., page 1 unnumbered and the remaining leaves numbered 2-11.
- Astoria, Chapter 60, by Washington Irving ca. 1835, AMs, 11 l., page 1 unnumbered and the remaining leaves numbered 2-7, 9-12, lacking a page 8.
- Astoria, Chapter 61, by Washington Irving ca. 1835, AMs, 22 l., page 1 unnumbered and the remaining leaves numbered 2-22.